#### SHIVANI MADWAL

Madwalshivani 1<u>995@gmail.com</u>

9643935426



**English and Hindi** 

A- 188, street number - 04 Tomor colony, Burari, Delhi - 84, India

# **OBJECTIVE**

A creative and motivated young professional with more than 6 years of work experience in Design management, with an eye for emerging and upcoming trends, who is able to work and co-ordinate effectively as a part of a team as well as under own initiative.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

 Designer & Product launch manager eShakti.com Private Limited

**2022-Present**: 26<sup>th</sup> of September 2016 – Present. <u>eShakti.com</u> Gurugram, Haryana, India

Professional Reference: Ms. Roopali Nair Senior Designer, India, eShakti.com Contact Number: +91 8527296798, Email Id: roopalinair@eshakti.com

<u>Professional Reference</u>: Ms. Carmella Heverin Chief Design Officer, New York, eShakti.com Email Id: <u>cheverin@eshakti.com</u>

 Designer cum merchant - Fades.com Private Limited (startup)

**2015-2016:** 2<sup>nd</sup> October 2015 - 31<sup>st</sup> July 2016 <u>Fades.com</u> Noida, India

<u>Professional Reference</u>: Ms. Triveni Joshi Head Designer, India, <u>Fades.com</u> Contact Number: +91 9560730185, Email Id: triveni7986@gmail.com

## **WORK RESPONSIBILITIES**

## eShakti.com (Design process)

- Managing design process from conception through final styling and update with emerging trends in fashion. Collaborating with team members to select seasonal and occasional themes, make edits to line and create new concepts.
- Conducting market and customer research to identify previous buying patterns and selecting new trends, fabrics, trims, techniques, seeking latest design inspirations and coming up with story, mood, theme and colour boards.
- Collaborating with prints and technical designers to ensure accurate prints and pattern development and make sure it is customizable according to the needs and size of the customer and Direct and coordinate with artisans involved in the craft of decorating fabric such as Hand and Manualmachine embroidery and Embellishment.

## **EDUCATION**

- **2012-2015**: Young men's christian association (YMCA), connaught place, New Delhi, India.

Bachelor of Design (B. Des.) in Fashion Technology

- **2010-2012**: C.B.S.E (Humanities), Shakti Nagar No. 1, Delhi, India.

## SKILLS

- Creative and conceptual strategic thinking and strong visualizing and listening skills.
- Time management and Project management skills.

- Tolerance of ambiguity and flexibility.
- Ability to perform well under pressure and take constructive criticism positively.
- Ability to initiate, coordinate, manage and implement major projects.
- General understanding of business, basic marketing principles and organizational processes.
- Strong research and presentation skills and basic analytical and quantitative skills.
- Great eye for emerging and upcoming trends.
- Ability to handle a wide variety of tasks.
- Positioning team members to use their talents optimally.
- Maintaining morale and workplace harmony.
- Proficient in Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft PowerPoint and Illustrator/Adobe Photoshop.

Declaration: I hereby declare that the above-mentioned information is correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.